myoptumhealth.com 2012-03-20

# Privacy and Security Policy - myOptumHealth

**I.            Introduction and Applicability**

           PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY AND SECURITY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS SITE. myOptumHealth.com, by Medical Network, Inc., a subsidiary of OptumHealth, Inc. (“OptumHealth”, “myOptumHealth”, “Site”, “we”, or “us”), is very sensitive to privacy and security issues. We respect your right to privacy and know that you want us to keep your information that you send to us secure. This Privacy and Security Policy (“Privacy Policy”), along with the myOptumHealth [Terms and Conditions](http://www.myoptumhealth.com/portal/TermOfUse), describe the terms and conditions under which we offer you access to our Services. 

           This Privacy Policy applies to all public OptumHealth Sites owned or operated by OptumHealth. OptumHealth may share information among its affiliates, subsidiaries, or sites that it owns or controls, but such information is always protected under the terms of this Privacy Policy. By using these services and this Site(s), you signify your agreement to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use these services. We may revise and update this Privacy Policy at any time, as detailed below. Your continued use of myOptumHealth will mean you accept those changes. 

**II.          Protecting Your Personal and Health Information**

           We have taken precautionary measures to make all information received from our online visitors secure against unauthorized access and use. We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our Site.

**III.         Information We Disclose About You**

           We do not sell or share your personal or identifiable information to companies outside of OptumHealth and its affiliates, with the exception that it may be necessary for us to provide your information to contracted external partners in order to respond to your inquiries and to provide you with services on your behalf. If we do this, our external partners may only use the information provided for the specified use and project and they are contractually bound to holding the information to the same or higher privacy and security standards as myOptumHealth.

           We may also provide your personal health information and that of other registered users in non-identifiable, aggregate form to third parties, but never in such a way that it violates your privacy.

           We will disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process.

**IV.         Personal Information We Collect About You**

           The myOptumHealth registration form requires users to give us contact information and some demographic information. To use some Site functions, users must volunteer personal health information (such as, height, weight, and past medical history). Depending on the function, you may need to provide personal information for full functionality.

           We may use demographic and personal health information to tailor your experience at our Site, show you the content in which we think you might be interested, and display content according to your preferences. Your health information is password-protected to prevent access by other users.

           We may conduct surveys on our Site in which we ask you and other visitors for contact information (such as your e-mail addresses). We use contact data from our surveys to send users information about our company. You have the option of choosing not to receive such e-mails at the time you register or at any time, as detailed below. 

           You may request that myOptumHealth.com delete personal, identifiable information it has retained about you. If you would like your information deleted, please contact us via myOptumHealth.com and provide us with your myOptumHealth user name and the e-mail address you provided to us. Or, you may submit your request via mail to:

Customer Service  
myOptumHealth.com  
Windsor Corporate Park  
50 Millstone Road, Building 200, Suite 160  
East Windsor, NJ 08520

**V.          Internet Information We Collect About You**

**A.            Cookies Technology**

           OptumHealth uses “cookies” technology to obtain usage information from our online visitors. “Cookies” do not identify a specific user and are not used to collect any personal information. A “cookie” is a message given to your Web browser by our Web server. The message is then sent back to our server each time your browser requests a page from our server. The “cookies” myOptumHealth uses are “session cookies”, which means they are erased from your computer when you close your Web browser. 

           You may disable your cookie information by adjusting your browser preferences on your personal computer at any time. In order to provide the best possible service and relevant information to you, we use cookies to:

o          Track resources and data accessed on the Site per visitor; 

o          Keep track of your password and to personalize your Web page; 

o          Record general Site statistics and activity; and 

o          Assist users experiencing Web Site problems. 

**B.            IP Address**

           We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Site. Your IP address may also may be used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. 

**C.            Online Communities**

           myOptumHealth provides public forums where you can share information with other users. Any posting, transmitting, or uploading (“Posting”) of any sort of text, photograph, video, audio or any other sort of content (“Material”) is public. **_Any Material you share in a Posting is by design open to the public and is not a private, secure service_**. myOptumHealth is not responsible for any material Posted, and you should exercise caution when Posting any personal Material, and consider not Posting personal material at all. 

**VI.         Our Online Communication Practices**

**A.            General Email Communications**

           We use information provided by you for internal purposes, to send you information about new myOptumHealth Site features, services, or updates, information about our company and promotional material or offers from some of our corporate partners, and other news. You will be given the opportunity to decline these services at the point of registration, and you may opt-out of receiving future mailings (see the Choice/Opt-out section following).

           We may send email communications to you related to general health benefits, Site updates, health conditions, and general health topics.

           Unless you are using our secure e-mail function, the email functionality on our Site does not provide a completely secure and confidential means of communication. It is possible that your email communication may be accessed or viewed inappropriately by another Internet user while in transit to us. If you wish to keep your information completely private, you should not use email.

**B.            Interactive Web Features**

           By accessing this Site, you agree that you certain interactive Web features you use may provide communications to you. In addition, you agree that we may use interactive tools while you are on the Site itself to contact you.

**C.            Links to Other Web Sites**

           This Site may contain links to other sites. myOptumHealth is not responsible for the security, privacy practices, or the content of such Web sites. Please read the privacy statements, terms and conditions, and any other legal information of the linked Web sites that you visit. 

**VII.        Communications Opt-Out**

           myOptumHealth provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from our partners and us. When you complete registration or when you make changes to your profile, you will be given the choice of receiving informational/promotional e-mails from myOptumHealth. You may opt-out of receiving e-mails on behalf of myOptumHealth at registration by updating the preference box for receiving e-mails and newsletters. You may also opt-out of receiving these e-mails and newsletters by changing your preferences in Communication Settings. You may remove all of the information you have stored with us through the "My Account" screen. You will be notified upon completion of the removal process.

**VIII.       Correction, Updating, and Removal of Your Information**

           This Site gives users the following options for opting out of receiving information from us, updating and removing personal information they have provided, and changing preferences with respect to receiving future communications: 

o                   You may correct, update, or remove your personal information yourself from the myOptumHealth tools that collect and store your data by going back to the specific tool, logging-in and making the desired changes; 

o                   You can [Contact Us](http://www.myoptumhealth.com/portal/ContactUs?contactView=form) at this link and request correction, updating, or removal of your information; 

o                   You can log onto our system and manage your profile settings through the “My Account page”; or, 

o                   You can send mail to the following postal address and request correction, updating, or removal of your information: 

                        myOptumHealth.com  
                        Windsor Corporate Park  
                        50 Millstone Road, Building 200, Suite 160  
                        East Windsor, NJ 08520

If you choose to remove or not supply us with personal information, you will be unable to access or fully use the functionality of some of myOptumHealth.com's features, such as the Personal Health Record and e-newsletters. You should also be aware that if you ask us to correct, update, or remove your information we will do so from our active databases, but it will not be feasible or possible to do so from our back-up media, nor is it technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information that you may have provided to myOptumHealth. 

**IX.         Notification of Changes**

           myOptumHealth may modify this Privacy Policy at any time in its discretion, so please review it frequently. If we are going to materially change our Privacy Policy regarding the use of your personally identifiable information, we will attempt to notify you at the e-mail address you provided, and post it prominently on our Site. Your continued use of myOptumHealth will indicate acceptance of any such material change, or you may opt-out of continuing to use the Site. 

           myOptumHealth may make non-material changes to the Privacy Policy that do not affect your personal or health information. For these instances, we may not notify you of such non-material changes.

           If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places appropriate throughout our Site so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

**X.          Contacting the Web Site**

           If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this Site or your dealings with this Site, you can [Contact Us](http://www.myoptumhealth.com/portal/ContactUs?contactView=form) online or via post:

Customer Service  
myOptumHealth.com  
Windsor Corporate Park  
50 Millstone Road, Building 200, Suite 160  
East Windsor, NJ 08520

|  Effective as of 4/27/2009  |   
---|---|---
